IURI MARTINHO

Experienced Porting / Unity Developer

+351 912706618 @ leitao.martinho@gmail.com Portugal

Blender



SKILLS

Unity Engine	Unreal Engine		
C# JavaScr	ipt _	Lua	JIRA
Google Suite Version control			
Game Maker Studios		VR/AR	

FIND ME ONLINE



LinkedIn

Console Development

https://www.linkedin.com/in/iur imartinho/

SUMMARY

Result-orientated developer with 6+ years of experience covering various projects and products including prototyping, developing, porting and supporting ongoing projects. A fast and eager learner, proven to be able to adapt to changing project requirements quickly to meet business goals.

EXPERIENCE

Nintendo Switch Ports

Nerd Monkeys

= 05/2019 - Present

From in house titles to outsourcing, I've ported multiple games from multiple engines to the Nintendo Switch

With the gathered information across the projects, I helped Nerd Monkeys achieve results and pave the way to streamline and improve future ports.

Tech Lead / Producer in Short Games Collection

Nerd Monkeys

= 08/2020 - 08/2021

Attps://www.nintendo.pt/-2041890.html

SGC is a collection of short games/experiences developed exclusively for the Nintendo Switch with unique games made by developers around the globe.

Lead a team of 6 developers to port all 6 games to the Nintendo Switch and design an interactive menu from scratch to encapsulate the experience.

Unity Development

Multiple Studios

= 2018

Creating projects from the start, prototyping, modding, and entering ongoing projects, I have worked with a multitude of teams developing for PC, consoles, and mobile platforms.

- Developed and implement tools and features on ongoing projects.
- Created proof of concepts and prototypes for new and existing ideas
- · Worked with various producers / work management tools and Source control software
- · I've also worked with universities and hospitals to develop experiences, from web to serious games.

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma, Videogames

ETIC Algarve

= 2016 - 2018

Digital Interface Professional Certificate, Communication Design

High School Tomás Cabreira

= 2013 - 2016

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

Native ••••

English

Proficient ●●●●

